Fayiz CJ

Personal Website | LinkedIn | GitHub |

Location: Kochi, Kerala, India Email: <u>fayizcj94@gmail.com</u> | Mobile: +91 9946340822

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Self-taught **MERN Full Stack** developer with **1 year** of industrial experience. I have a solid grasp of **RESTAPIs,NoSQL databases, Node.js, React.js** and more. I have a strong technical foundation in software development and An ability to work together with a large team, Skill with multitasking and time management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks : Express Servers : Node.js

Libraries : React.js, Redux, React Router

Cloud Platforms: AmazonWebServices(AWS)EC2,Netlify, DigitalOcean

Databases : MongoDB,PostgreSQL

version Controls: Git, GitHub
API Development: RESTful API
API Testing: Postman
API Testing: MVC

EXPERIENCE

MERN Full Stack Developer Intern

jan 2023 – Present Remote – Kochi, Kerala, India

Besent Technologies

- I designed and deployed a high-performance E-commerce website that is interactive and adaptable, using
 Handlebars, CSS, JavaScript. I utilized advanced technologies such as Node.js, Express.js, Mongoose, and
 MongoDB for this e-commerce project. It was organized following a Model-View-Controller (MVC) approach, which
 ensures easy management and scalability
- Worked with **REST APIs** to retrieve and display data from databases
- I have experience working with AWS setting up automated deployment processes using GitHub Actions for Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment(CI/CD)

Front End with React js

jan 2022 – sep 2022 Banglore, Karnataka, India

Besent Technologies

- Worked with MVC frameworks to develop robust and scalable backends
- Troubleshot and fixed bugs and issues in the backend to ensure smooth operation of the applications

Technical Support Engineer

Apr 2020 - Sep 2021

• Aabasoft is a client oriented company. Our philosophy is to have the client at the focus point of all discussions and planning **Packetloss**, **Power level**, **and Troubleshooting**

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Al-Ameen College, Mahatma Gandhi University Kottayam

Aluva, Kochi, India Jan 2017 – Apr 2020

Dedicated and highly motivated Computer Science graduate with a BSc in Computer Science seeking a challenging position in the field to apply my technical skills and knowledge in software development and problem-solving

Fresh-Hub E-commerce website

Handlebars, CSS, Nodejs, Express.js, MongoDB, Git, AWS

Source Code

- I designed and developed a modern website using **Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB** utilized technologies like **Handlebars,CSS, and JavaScript**
- This project involved creating a tailored food ordering website for a specific restaurant, guaranteeing a seamless and enjoyable dining experience for users
- Implemented session and cookies for authentication, with Twilio Authentication API for 2FA.
- Integrated Razorpay for payment processing, supporting both online payments and COD.
- I implemented an MVC architecture to manage and scale the application effectively.
- The application was hosted on AWS EC2 with nginx for reliable and scalable deployment
- I also set up automated deployment processes using GitHub Actions for Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD).

User Managemnet System

React.js, Node.js, Express, JavaScript, MongoDB Git

Source Code

- A Create a user schema with fields such as name, email, password, and points to store user information and their points
- Build the React frontend for user management. Create components for displaying user information and implementing the point system. You can use Axios or the fetch API to make HTTP requests to your Express API. **Express**

Crud operation

React.js, MockApi, axios, JavaScript, Git

Source Code

- Build a React.js CRUD Application to consume Web API, display and modify data with Router, Axios, Mock Api Naterial UI
- React Tutorial Application in that:- Add User, Update User, DeleteUser, ViewUsers

Netflix

React.js,Redux,Context, JavaScript, Api, Git

Source Code

- Developed a Netflix clone web application using React and Axios, allowing users to browse and watch their favorite
 movies and TV shows
- Implemented features such as user authentication and search functionality

Portfolio

React, javascript, Tailwind, Bootstarp, Git

Source Code

- take on responsive React portfolio website from scratch using Tailwind CSS and deploying it to server
- We can learn a lot of amazing things including tailwind, smooth scroll, adding social icons, custom fonts, gradient background, and responsive design
- Deploying the project we will be using **Netlify**. We will use **tailwind** for our CSS instead of using custom CSS.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Front end with Reacjt js
- · Programming with c++
- Mern stack Developer